<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>GFS on Juan's Blog</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/</link><description>Recent content in GFS on Juan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GEE Python API and Precipitation Forecasting - Part 1</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/gfs_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/gfs_1/</guid><description>Project Overview Greetings! Welcome to the first part of a deep dive into Google Earth Engine (GEE) and its Python API. In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to leverage the power of GEE for geospatial analysis, focusing on precipitation forecasting using the Global Forecast System (GFS) dataset.
GFS is a widely-used weather forecast model developed by NOAA. It provides comprehensive weather data, including temperature, wind, and precipitation forecasts, on a global scale.</description></item><item><title>GEE Python API and Precipitation Forecasting - Part 2</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/gfs_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gfs/gfs_2/</guid><description>Project Overview Hello again! Welcome to the continuation of our deep dive into precipitation forecasting using the GFS dataset and the GEE Python API. In our previous post, we demonstrated how to use the GEE Python API along with the XEE library (an integration of GEE and xarray) to forecast precipitation for specific coordinates. This time, we’re going to expand our analysis to cover an entire region. Besides, we&amp;rsquo;ll leverage additional libraries such as Geopandas and Cartopy to create comprehensive spatial maps of precipitation forecasts.</description></item></channel></rss>