<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Juan's Blog</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Juan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GEE Python API and CHIRPS: Analyzing precipitation in Buenos Aires - Part 1</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_1/</guid><description>Project Overview Welcome back! In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the severe drought that affected Buenos Aires Province in Argentina, in 2023, using the CHIRPS dataset and the Google Earth Engine (GEE) Python API.
As detailed in the GEE catalog, CHIRPS—short for Climate Hazards Group InfraRed Precipitation with Station data—is a 30+ year quasi-global rainfall dataset. This dataset integrates satellite imagery with in-situ station data at a 0.05° resolution to generate gridded rainfall at daily temporal resolution.</description></item><item><title>GEE Python API and CHIRPS: Analyzing precipitation in Buenos Aires - Part 2</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_2/</guid><description>Project Overview In this post, we continue our exploration of the 2023 severe drought in Buenos Aires province, Argentina. In our previous post, we used the CHIRPS dataset to analyze the extent and impact of the drought. Now, we’ll take our analysis a step further by extracting time series data from specific coordinates within the affected region.
To ensure that you can follow along and reproduce the results, all the code used in this analysis is available in my GitHub repository.</description></item><item><title>GEE Python API and Precipitation Forecasting - Part 1</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/gfs/gfs_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/gfs/gfs_1/</guid><description>Project Overview Greetings! Welcome to the first part of a deep dive into Google Earth Engine (GEE) and its Python API. In this series, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to leverage the power of GEE for geospatial analysis, focusing on precipitation forecasting using the Global Forecast System (GFS) dataset.
GFS is a widely-used weather forecast model developed by NOAA. It provides comprehensive weather data, including temperature, wind, and precipitation forecasts, on a global scale.</description></item><item><title>GEE Python API and Precipitation Forecasting - Part 2</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/gfs/gfs_2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/gfs/gfs_2/</guid><description>Project Overview Hello again! Welcome to the continuation of our deep dive into precipitation forecasting using the GFS dataset and the GEE Python API. In our previous post, we demonstrated how to use the GEE Python API along with the XEE library (an integration of GEE and xarray) to forecast precipitation for specific coordinates. This time, we’re going to expand our analysis to cover an entire region. Besides, we&amp;rsquo;ll leverage additional libraries such as Geopandas and Cartopy to create comprehensive spatial maps of precipitation forecasts.</description></item><item><title>QGIS: Batch Processing</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/qgis/qgis_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/qgis/qgis_1/</guid><description>Project Overview In this tutorial, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore the capabilities of batch processing in QGIS. Batch processing is incredibly helpful for repetitive tasks that can otherwise consume a lot of time and effort. By automating these tasks, you can focus on more important aspects of your project, increasing both efficiency and productivity.
Let me set up an example where we&amp;rsquo;ll fully leverage the power of batch processing in QGIS.
Case Example We&amp;rsquo;ve got a set of 10 MODIS land surface temperature (LST) images for an area of interest.</description></item></channel></rss>