<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>CHIRPS on Juan's Blog</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/</link><description>Recent content in CHIRPS on Juan's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>GEE Python API and CHIRPS: Analyzing precipitation in Buenos Aires - Part 2</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_2/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-overview">Project Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>In this post, we continue our exploration of the 2023 severe drought in Buenos Aires province, Argentina. In our previous post, we used the CHIRPS dataset to analyze the extent and impact of the drought. Now, we’ll take our analysis a step further by extracting time series data from specific coordinates within the affected region.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To ensure that you can follow along and reproduce the results, all the code used in this analysis is available in my &lt;a href="https://github.com/jm-marcenaro/hugo-posts/tree/main/GEE%20Python%20API%20-%20CHIRPS" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub repository&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GEE Python API and CHIRPS: Analyzing precipitation in Buenos Aires - Part 1</title><link>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_1/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2024 08:06:25 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://hugo-toha.github.io/posts/gee/chirps/chirps_1/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="project-overview">Project Overview&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Welcome back! In this post, we&amp;rsquo;ll delve into the severe drought that affected Buenos Aires Province in Argentina, in 2023, using the CHIRPS dataset and the Google Earth Engine (GEE) Python API.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As detailed in the &lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/earth-engine/datasets/catalog/UCSB-CHG_CHIRPS_DAILY" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GEE catalog&lt;/a>, CHIRPS—short for Climate Hazards Group InfraRed Precipitation with Station data—is a 30+ year quasi-global rainfall dataset. This dataset integrates satellite imagery with in-situ station data at a 0.05° resolution to generate gridded rainfall at daily temporal resolution. This dataset is invaluable for trend analysis and seasonal drought monitoring.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>